Gerrit Smith Papers
Gerrit Smith Papers
- Business and land files
  - Land Documents
    - List of land holdings
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 103)
      - Miscellaneous, 1803-1838; 1844-1871; undated; 6 folders (Box 104)
      - Purchased at tax sales, 1821-1871; 3 folders (Box 105)
      - List of lands in various counties purchased at tax sales (vol.57a), undated (Box 105)
    - Locations of lots, 1819-1830s
      - List of locations of land, arranged by county (vol.58), undated (Volume 58)
      - List of locations of land, arranged by county (vol.59), undated (Volume 59)
      - List of locations of land (vol.60), undated (Box 105)
      - List of locations of land, arranged by county (vol.61), undated (Box 105)
      - List of locations of land in the Old Military Tract (vol.62), undated (Box 105)
      - List of locations of land, arranged by county (vol.63), undated (Box 105)
      - List of locations of land (vol.64), 1819 (Box 105)
      - List of locations of land in Madison and Oneida Counties (vol.64a), undated (Box 106)
      - List of locations of land, unidentified (vol.64b), undated (Box 106)
      - List of locations of land in the Old Military Tract (vol.64c), undated (Box 106)
      - List of locations of land, unidentified (vol.64d), undated (Box 106)
    - Purchases and sales, accounts of, 1799-1910
      - Unidentified (vol.64e), undated (Box 106)
      - Crosby's Manor and Jerseyfield Patent (vol.64f), undated (Box 106)
      - First township in Chenango Triangle (vol.64g), undated (Box 106)
      - First township in Chenango Triangle (vol.64h), undated (Box 106)
      - First township in Chenango Triangle (vol.64i), undated (Box 106)
      - First township in Chenango Triangle (vol.64j), undated (Box 106)
      - Old Military Tract, Abstract No. 1 (vol.65), 1827-1833 (Box 106)
      - Old Military Tract, Abstract No.2 (vol.66), 1833-1835 (Box 106)
      - Lands westward, New York State (vol.67), 1821; 1832 (Box 106)
      - Lands owned by Dr. John D. Henry and Gerrit Smith (vol.67a), 1816-1823 (Box 106)
      - Lands in the town of Florence, Oneida County, the fourth township in Scriba's Patent (vol.68), 1818-1822 (Box 106)
      - Land Book C of Peter Smith, and the Lake 0neida Reservation (vol.68a), 1814-1825 (Box 106)
      - Peter Smith's memos regarding purchases for arrears of quit rent and taxes (vol.69), 1826-1834 (Box 107)
      - Tax land book of properties acquired by New York State tax sales in 1814 and 1815, 1829 (Box 107)
      - Accounts, with an abstract of earlier land books (vol.70), 1799-1829 (Volume 70)
      - Land book No. 1, includes all lands owned by Peter Smith at the time of his death in 1837 (vol.71), 1810-1854 (Volume 71)
      - Accounts (vol.72), 1819-1837 (Volume 72)
      - Accounts (vol.73), 1821-1854 (Volume 73)
      - List of all lands in which Gerrit Smith has any interest, compiled to facilitate making up tax lists (vol.74), 1824 (Volume 74)
      - Record of lands purchased at tax sales (vol.75), 1826-1830 (Volume 75)
      - Record of lands purchased at tax sale, Oswego (vol.76), 1827-1835 (Volume 76)
      - Record of purchases made after 1819 and taxes upon this property (vol.77), 1824-1837 (Volume 77)
      - Land Book G, of trust estate lands and sales (vol.78), 1827-1864 (Volume 78)
      - Great Book No. 2, continued from Great Book (vol.79), 1828-1852 (Volume 79)
      - Land Book H of trust estate lands and sales, 1837-1866 (Volume 80)
      - Land Book I of trust estate lands and sales, 1839-1864 (Volume 81)
      - Land Book K, 1846-1866 (Volume 82)
      - Land Book L, 1848-1871; includes lists of persons receiving free land (Volume 83)
      - Records of land bought at tax sales, 1850 (Volume 84)
      - Land Book M, 1853-1873 (Volume 85)
      - Land Book No. 3 (vol.86), 1858-1869 (Volume 86)
      - Land Book N, 1869-1910 (Volume 87)
      - Land Book [J?], includes lists of land distributed among colored men in 1846 (vol.88), 1844-1877 (Volume 88)
      - Receipts for land purchased of New York State at public auction, 1825-1859 (Box 107)
      - Records of accounts of land payments, 1836-1874 (Box 107)
      - Records of accounts of lands purchased, miscellaneous, 1817-1860; undated (Box 107)
      - Redemption of land for back taxes, certificates and tax lists, undated (Box 107)
      - Redemption of land for back taxes, certificates and tax lists, 1830-1879; 5 folders (Box 108)
    - Surveyors' records
      - (vol.88a through 88f), 1796-1835; 10 volumes in 1 folder (Box 109)
        See also Land Book [J?] (vol.88), which includes descriptions and maps.
        Field book of 84 lots of land in Killarney township, McCombs Purchase, surveyed by Nathan Ward, 1823-1824 (vol.88a); Township 9 & 10 of the Old Military Tract, minutes by [Nathan] Ward, 1832-1833 (vols.88b, 88b1, 88b2, 88b5); Killarney township, McCombs Purchase, undated (vol.88c); Townships 27 and 46, Totten and Crossfield's Purchase, 1796 (vol.88d); Gore, western part of Refugee Tract, Champlain township, minutes by Nathan Ward, 1833 (vol.88e); Essex County, Old Military Tract, township 12, Thorn's survey, undated (vol.88f)
      - (vol.88g through 88k), 5 volumes in 1 folder (Box 109)
        Jay Tract, Old Military Tract, township 3, minutes by John H. Smith, 1835 (vol.88g); Hyde Township, minutes by John H. Smith, 1835 (vol.88h); Township 11, Totten and Crossfield's Purchase, minutes by John H. Smith, 1835 (vol.88i); Unidentified, David S. Crandal, 1830 (vol.88j); Unidentified, James Frost, 1830 (vol.88k)
      - (vol.88L through 88o), 4 volumes in 1 folder (Box 109)
        Charlotte River Patent, a resurvey of sundry lots and parts by Benj. Overbagh, May – June 1831 (vol.88L); Boundaries and partial description of sundry farms and lots in Byrne's Patent, Schoharie County, re-surveyed and subdivided by Benjamin Overbagh, June - Aug. 1831 (vol.88m); Old Military Tract, township 10, re-surveyed by Nathan Ward, 1834-1835 (vol.88n); Old Military Tract township 10, 14 lots, 9 of which are subdivided by Nathan Ward, September 1835 (vol.88o)
      - (vol.89 and 89a), 2 volumes in 1 folder (Box 109)
        Chenango Triangle, map book, undated (vol.89); unidentified field book, undated (vol.89a)
      - Surveyor's notes, field books and maps
        - Miscellaneous, 1775-1872; undated; 2 folders (Box 109)
        - Miscellaneous, 1775-1872; undated; 5 folders (Box 110)
    - Treasurer's receipts for land purchased from New York State, 1810-1876; 8 folders (Box 111)
  - Legal documents
    - Miscellaneous, 1820-1874; undated; 4 folders (Box 112)
    - Agreements for land purchases
      - Ab – Ac, 1826-1854 (Box 112)
      - Ad, 1829-1861 (Box 112)
      - Ag – Ak, 1815-1854 (Box 112)
      - Ai – Ak, 1815-1846 (Box 112)
      - Al, 1819-1856; 4 folders (Box 112)
      - Am, 1814-1852; 2 folders (Box 112)
      - An, 1830-1864; 2 folders (Box 112)
      - Ar, 1838-1851 (Box 113)
      - Ar – At, 1824-1851 (Box 113)
      - Au – Av, 1827-1853 (Box 113)
      - Ax – Ay, 1826-1845 (Box 113)
      - Ba, 1809-1865; 9 folders (Box 113)
      - Be, 1814-1867; 7 folders (Box 113)
      - Bi, 1823-1873; 5 folders (Box 114)
      - Bl, 1822-1857 (Box 114)
      - Bo, 1820-1870 (Box 114)
      - Br, 1811-1864; 4 folders (Box 114)
      - Bu, 1818-1877; 6 folders (Box 115)
      - By, 1826-1858 (Box 115)
      - Fragments (Box 115)
      - Ca, 1879-1874; 4 folders (Box 115)
      - Ch, 1823-1862; 4 folders (Box 116)
      - Cl, 1807-1863; 3 folders (Box 116)
      - Co, 1807-1866; 18 folders (Box 116)
      - Fragments (Box 116)
      - Cr, 1824-1859 (Box 117)
      - Cu – Cy, 1822-1851 (Box 117)
      - Da, 1827-1871; 3 folders (Box 117)
      - De, 1823-1873; 2 folders (Box 117)
      - Di, 1829-1861 (Box 117)
      - Do, 1821-1863 (Box 118)
      - Dr, 1820-1841 (Box 118)
      - Du, 1822-1868 (Box 118)
      - Dw – Dy, 1827-1850 (Box 118)
      - Ea – Ec, 1834-1858 (Box 118)
      - Ed, 1821-1858 (Box 118)
      - Eg – El, 1814-1851 (Box 118)
      - Em – En, 1827-1854 (Box 118)
      - Er – Ev, 1824-1845 (Box 118)
      - Fa, 1822-1859; 3 folders (Box 119)
      - Fe, 1824-1858 (Box 119)
      - Fi, 1824-1869; 4 folders (Box 119)
      - Fl, 1817-1856 (Box 119)
      - Fo, 1818-1867; 3 folders (Box 119)
      - Fr, 1821-1858; 3 folders (Box 119)
      - Fu, 1827-1852; 2 folders (Box 119)
      - Ga, 1827-1870; 2 folders (Box 120)
      - Ge, 1829-1851 (Box 120)
      - Gi, 1824-1857; 2 folders (Box 120)
      - Gl, 1848-1865 (Box 120)
      - Go, 1821-1874; 3 folders (Box 120)
      - Gr, 1812-1865; 5 folders (Box 120)
      - Gu, 1838-1842 (Box 120)
      - Ha, 1818-1866; 7 folders (Box 121)
      - He, 1816-1858; 2 folders (Box 122)
      - Hi, 1821-1858; 2 folders (Box 122)
      - Ho, 1825-1864; 3 folders (Box 122)
      - Hu, 1816-1858; 2 folders (Box 123)
      - Hy, 1821-1860 (Box 123)
      - In, 1819-1853 (Box 123)
      - Ir – Iv, 1831-1855 (Box 123)
      - Ja, 1826-1850 (Box 123)
      - Je, 1825-1839 (Box 123)
      - Jo, 1818-1862; 3 folders (Box 123)
      - Ju, 1825-1854 (Box 123)
      - Ke, 1820-1869; 2 folders (Box 123)
      - Ke, 1820-1874; 2 folders (Box 124)
      - Ki, 1825-1864; 2 folders (Box 124)
      - Kl, 1826-1865 (Box 124)
      - Kn – Ky, 1820-1854 (Box 124)
      - La, 1826-1855; 3 folders (Box 124)
      - Le, 1815-1874; 2 folders (Box 124)
      - Li, 1814-1860 (Box 125)
      - Ll, 1831-1851 (Box 125)
      - Lo, 1814-1862; 2 folders (Box 125)
      - Lu, 1819-1847 (Box 125)
      - Ly, 1817-1855 (Box 125)
      - Ma, 1822-1862; 4 folders (Box 125)
      - Mc, 1824-1867; 2 folders (Box 125)
      - Mc, 1825-1866; 2 folders (Box 126)
      - Me, 1819-1866; 3 folders (Box 126)
      - Mi, 1817-1881; 3 folders (Box 126)
      - Mo, 1815-1858; 3 folders (Box 126)
      - Mu, 1828-1860 (Box 127)
      - My, 1818-1858 (Box 127)
      - Na, 1810-1856 (Box 127)
      - Ne, 1823-1863 (Box 127)
      - Ni, 1822-1860 (Box 127)
      - No, 1813-1857 (Box 127)
      - Nu – Ny, 1813-1847 (Box 127)
      - Ob – Ol, 1815-1866 (Box 127)
      - On – Or, 1824-1870 (Box 127)
      - Os – Ow, 1813-1874 (Box 127)
      - Pa, 1817-1871; 4 folders (Box 127)
      - Pe, 1814-1874; 2 folders (Box 128)
      - Ph, 1822-1853 (Box 128)
      - Pi – Pl, 1815-1858 (Box 128)
      - Po, 1822-1863; 2 folders (Box 128)
      - Pr, 1814-1874 (Box 128)
      - Pu, 1814-1863 (Box 128)
      - Qu, 1830-1853 (Box 128)
      - Ra, 1814-1865; 2 folders (Box 129)
      - Re, 1826-1869; 2 folders (Box 129)
      - Rh, 1847-1855 (Box 129)
      - Ri, 1814-1866; 2 folders (Box 129)
      - Ro, 1818-1874; 5 folders (Box 129)
      - Ru, 1825-1876; 2 folders (Box 130)
      - Ry, 1839-1872 (Box 130)
      - Sa, 1820-1859; 2 folders (Box 130)
      - Sc, 1827-1874 (Box 130)
      - Se, 1835-1849 (Box 130)
      - Sh, 1825-1873; 3 folders (Box 130)
      - Si, 1832-1869 (Box 130)
      - Sk, 1823-1860 (Box 130)
      - Sl, 1813-1854 (Box 131)
      - Sm, 1812-1872; 4 folders (Box 131)
      - Sn, 1821-1860 (Box 131)
      - So, 1815-1845 (Box 131)
      - Sp, 1814-1863; 2 folders (Box 131)
      - Sq, 1833 (Box 131)
      - St, 1816-1865 (Box 131)
      - St, 1816-1865; 4 folders (Box 132)
      - Su, 1824-1869 (Box 132)
      - Sw, 1824-1858 (Box 132)
      - Ta, 1823-1871 (Box 132)
      - Te, 1823-1848 (Box 132)
      - Th, 1814-1864 (Box 132)
      - Ti, 1821-1862 (Box 133)
      - To, 1823-1869 (Box 133)
      - Tr, 1820-1850 (Box 133)
      - Tu, 1821-1874 (Box 133)
      - Tw – Ty, 1825-1849 (Box 133)
      - U, 1824-1847 (Box 133)
      - V, 1827-1861 (Box 133)
      - Wa, 1816-1864 (Box 133)
      - Wa, 1816-1855 (Box 134)
      - We, 1816-1865 (Box 134)
      - Wh, 1828-1861 (Box 134)
      - Wi, 1824-1879 (Box 134)
      - Wo, 1814-1846; 2 folders (Box 135)
      - Wr – Wy, 1829-1851 (Box 135)
      - Y, 1816-1848 (Box 135)
      - Fragments (Box 135)
    - Bond, 1793-1874; undated (Box 135)
    - Caleb Calkins' files
      - Justice of the Peace records, 1857-1862; 2 folders (Box 135)
      - Miscellaneous legal records, 1857-1877 (Box 136)
    - Deeds, federal bounty lands purchased in Michigan by Gerrit Smith, 1853-1860 (Package 1)
    - Deeds and indentures
      - 1824-1834, 12 folders (Box 136)
      - 1835-1840, 10 folders (Box 137)
      - 1840-1844, 8 folders (Box 138)
      - 1845-1853, 11 folders (Box 139)
      - 1854-1869, 12 folders (Box 140)
      - 1871-1874 (Box 141)
    - Mortgages, 1827-1882 (Box 141)
    - Notes and judgements
      - General, 1859-1872; undated (Box 141)
      - List of land purchases and legal actions taken against the purchaser (vol.89b), undated (Box 141)
    - Suits, general
      - Howard vs. Smith, 1866 (Box 141)
      - Marble vs. McMinn, 1870; printed material (Box 141)
      - New York vs. Ambrecht, 1860 (Box 141)
      - Sayles vs. Smith, 1819-1845 (Box 141)
      - Smith vs. Oswego Rail Road, 1866 (Box 141)
      - Smith vs. Sanger, 1850 (Box 141)
      - Varick vs. Smith, undated (Box 141)
    - Suits, property
      - Books of Suits N. 1 (vol.90), 1818-1833; contains a list of suits, judgments, etc. re estate of Peter Smith (Box 141)
      - Book of Suits (vol.91), 1851-1855 (Box 141)
      - Book of Suits (vol.92), 1843; compilation of first two suit books (Box 141)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 142)
      - Miscellaneous, 1820; 1827-1842; 16 folders (Box 142)
      - Miscellaneous, 1843-1846; 8 folders (Box 143)
      - Miscellaneous, 1846-1868; 5 folders (Box 144)
    - Summonses and complaints
      - [General], 1836-1873; undated; 8 folders (Box 144)
      - Justice of the Peace docket (vol.92a), 1857-1860 (Box 144)
    - Wills and estates of relatives
      - Biddle, Mary Livingston Cochran, 1891 (Box 144)
      - Smith, Gerrit P., 1817-1836; 3 folders (Box 144)
      - Smith, Peter, 1834-1837; undated; 2 folders (Box 144)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1856-1888 (Box 145)
  - Subject files
    - Bunner, Elizabeth, properties, 1843-1857 (Box 145)
    - Canastota and Morrisville Plank Road Company
      - Legal and financial records, 1849-1850; 2 folders (Box 145)
      - Vouchers, bills and receipts, 1850 (Box 145)
    - Cochrane property, 1827-1839 (Box 145)
    - Gifts of land and money, 1846-1855
      - To Negroes, 1846-1854 (Box 145)
      - To poor whites of Madison County and New York State
        - Correspondence, 1847-1855; 3 folders (Box 145)
          See also Land Book [J?] (vol.88), which includes "Lists of lands distributed among colored men 1846".
        - Financial papers, receipts, and miscellaneous documents, 1847-1852; 2 folders (Box 145)
    - Hamilton College, 1867-1868; correspondence (Box 145)
    - Howard Insurance Company, 1828-1835; financial and legal papers (Box 146)
    - Oneida Turnpike Company
      - Minutes of meetings of directors and stock holders, 1801-1805 (Box 146)
      - Financial records, 1806-1810 (Box 146)
      - Legal records, 1802-1812 (Box 146)
      - Stocks, 1801-1809 (Box 146)
      - Toll receipts, 1806-1808 (Box 146)
    - Oswego Canal Company
      - Financial accounts, 1830-1853; 2 folders (Box 146)
      - Legal records, 1823-1857 (Box 146)
      - Dispute with H. Seymour, 1830-1831; undated (Box 146)
    - Peterboro Glass Factory
      - Agreements, 1819-1820 (Box 146)
      - Census of Manufacturers, Gerrit Smith's description of the Peterboro works, 1820; copy from the National Archives (Box 146)
      - Financial records, 1819-1822 (Box 146)
    - Rock Oil Company (vol.93), 1861-1862; minute book (Box 146)
    - Saint Lawrence County lands, 1851-1870; financial records (Box 146)
    - Saranac lands, 1837-1873; financial records (Box 146)
    - Tax title disputes, 1849-1852; legal papers (Box 147)
    - Tioga County, Pennsylvania lands, 1856-1867; correspondence, legal and financial records, map of holdings (Box 147)
- Writings
  - By Gerrit Smith
    - Fragments, holograph, undated (Box 147)
    - Autobiographical sketch, holograph, undated (Box 147)
    - Articles, public letters and speeches, 1823-1874; undated
      Almost all of these items, comprising several hundred letters, pamphlets, broadsides, speeches and so on, have been removed from the collection and cataloged individually. Please refer to and search for "Smith, Gerrit, 1797-1874" as author for a complete listing and detailed description. These items have also been digitized and are available online through the
      Gerrit Smith Pamphlets and Broadsides Collection
      . The few items that remain in the collection are listed below. Note that boxes 148 and 149 no longer exist.
      - To the editor of the Advocate of Temperance, published in Albany, 7 Apr 1835; holograph (Box 147)
      - To the members of the Liberty Party, circa 1840; letter, holograph (Box 147)
      - The Liberty Votes of the Town of Smithfield, to the Friends of the Slave in the County of Madison, 9 Feb 1843; letter, holograph (Box 147)
      - To the Democrats of the County of Madison, Aug 1844; letter, holograph (Box 147)
      - Gerrit Smith to Adain Ballou, 25 Oct 1844; newspaper clipping (Box 147)
      - [Miscellaneous, relating to Rev. Asa Rand's charges against Smith], 1845 (Box 147)
        "To my Neighbors," Oct 1845, holograph; Notice, 1845, holograph; and another "To my Neighbors, 1845, holograph
      - To the Public, 12 May 1852; call for the convention of the Liberty Party; holograph (Box 150)
      - Gerrit Smith on the future state, 21 Jan 1875; newspaper clipping (Box 150)
      - A Beautiful Letter for Boys [on the smoking of tobacco], printed material (Box 150)
      - A Story. The Ruinous Visit to Monkeyville, holograph, 15 Nov 1851 (Box 150)
      - [Southern Arrogance & Violence], undated; newspaper clipping (Box 150)
      - Gerrit Smith on temperance, undated; newspaper clipping (Box 150)
      - Published speeches, letters, broadsides, with index (vol.94), 1835-1874 (Box 150)
        Some of these are not included in the cataloged / scanned items.
    - Verse
      - Verse by Gerrit Smith and others, bound (vol.95), 1837-1874; holograph and printed material (Box 150)
      - Verse by Gerrit Smith and others, unbound, 1820-1875; holograph and printed material (Box 150)
  - By others
    - Cochran, John, "Has the Jury the Right of Judging Both of the Law, and the Fact?", undated; holograph, 7pp. (Box 150)
    - Cowper, H. Augustus, "Slavery in Brazil", 1843; printed material, 7pp.; includes holograph copy in the hand of Gerrit Smith of Benjamín Franklin's Petition to Congress, 1790 Feb.2 (Box 150)
    - Gates, Seth M. "Answer of the Hon. Seth M. Gates, to the Letter of Gerrit Smith." LeRoy Gazette-Extra, 30 Oct 1839; broadside (Box 150)
    - Green, S.W. Gerrit Smith's "Biography" To the editor of the Library Table, 20 Mar 1878; broadside (Box 150)
    - Hawley, Rev. Francis. A Review of Hon. Gerrit Smith's Discourse Setting Forth the Claims of a New Religion...Delivered in the Presbyterian Church, Sabbath, April 11, 1858. Syracuse: Daily Journal, printed material (Box 150)
    - H,. T. On Reconstruction, circa 1870; broadside (Box 150)
    - Jay, Judge [William] "Influence of Slavery in the Free States", 1853; holograph, 44pp. (Box 150)
    - Keppel, David "The Religious Experience of Hon. Gerrit Smith", circa 1874; newspaper clipping (Box 150)
    - K[eppel], David "Gerrit Smith's Christian Experience", circa 1874; newspaper clipping (Box 150)
    - Key, Francis Scott "Hymn" and "If Life's Pleasures Charm Thee", undated; holograph copy in Smith's hand; 1 leaf (2pp.) (Box 150)
    - Lake, Lydia "My Grandmother's Muff", undated; holograph, 12 pp. (Box 150)
    - New York Manumission Society, "Extracts from the I Vol. minutes of the New York Manumission Society, 1785-1797", undated; holograph copy in an unidentified hand, 8pp. (Box 150)
    - "American Conventions for Promoting the Abolition of Slavery and Improving the Conditions of the African Race", undated; holograph copy in the same unidentified hand, 9pp. (Box 150)
    - Sherwood, Lorenzo, 5 Feb 1867; letter, possibly to Gerrit Smith; broadside (Box 150)
    - Sullivan, William, "What smoking did in one case," Boston, 23 Sep 1872; holograph, 3pp, (Box 150)
    - "Gerrit Smith and the Vigilant Association of the City of New York," New York: John A. Gray, printer, 1860 (Box 150)
    - "Slavery and Marriage: A Dialogue," [Oneida Community], 1850; printed material (Box 150)
- Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 150)
  - Broadsides, 1813-1870 (Box 150)
  - Brown, John, circa 1850-1871; correspondence related to legal papers: land deed including John Brown's signature, and printed matter and photocopies by and about (Box 150)
  - Chaplin, William L., 1849-1873; correspondence re, including correspondence of William H. Seward, David A. Hall, William Goodell, Lewis Tappan and others, holograph; 2 folders (Box 151)
  - Gerrit Smith vs. the Chicago Tribune, 1865-1867; correspondence, legal and financial papers, and clippings re John Brown's raid on Harper's Ferry and Smith's subsequent insanity; 3 folders (Box 151)
  - Church of Peterboro
    - Correspondence, 1835-1871 (Box 151)
    - Memoranda and notes of Gerrit Smith, 1842-1849; undated (Box 151)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1850-1852 (Box 151)
    - Open letters, 1849-1859; undated (Box 151)
    - Ownership of pews (Presbyterian Church), 1821-1871 (Box 151)
    - Resolutions and creed, 1841-1869; undated (Box 151)
  - Clippings
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 151)
    - Miscellaneous, 1836-1879; 21 folders (Box 151)
    - Miscellaneous, 1885; 1892-1962; 6 folders (Box 152)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 152)
  - Miller, Elizabeth Smith. Common Place Book, 72L (vol.99), circa 1851-1889; holograph (Box 152)
  - Congressional term, 30th and 33rd Congresses
    - Miscellaneous printed and holograph material, 1852 (Box 152)
    - "An Act to Suppress Insurrection, to Punish Treason and Rebellion, to Seize and Confiscate the Property of Rebels, and for Other Purposes", 1862; holograph, 8pp. (Box 152)
    - Ex. Doc. no.19, 1848; printed material (Box 152)
    - Ex. Doc. no.46, 1854; printed material (Box 152)
    - Report Bill no.239, printed material (Box 152)
    - Report on Richard W. Meade, 1853; printed material (Box 152)
  - Draftees and volunteers in Madison County, 1863-1864; correspondence and notes, holograph (Box 152)
  - "The Hour and the Man", 1858; financial records, holograph, 11 leaves (Box 152)
  - Imprisonment of Jefferson Davis, 1866; correspondence and clippings (Box 152)
  - Jerry Rescue, 1851-1859; printed material; 2 folders (Box 152)
  - Kansas Relief, "Destitution in Kansas", 1856-1860; broadside to citizens of Kansas and holograph notes (Box 152)
  - Liberty Party, 1845-1850; lists of subscribers, voter tally sheets and miscellaneous material, holograph (Box 152)
  - List of anti-slavery men, circa 1842; holograph, 8 pp. paperbound (Box 152)
  - Madison County Protective Mercantile Association, undated; constitution and by-laws, printed, 6 pp. (Box 152)
  - New York Central College, McGrawville
    - Correspondence, 1852-1864 (Box 152)
    - Financial and legal records, 1858-1861 (Box 152)
    - Printed matter, 1850-1860 (Box 152)
  - Obituaries, Gerrit Smith, 1874-1875; newspaper clippings; 2 folders (Box 152)
  - Peterboro Academy (also Evans Academy)
    - Miscellaneous, 1851 (Box 152)
    - Accounts, 1851-1877 (Box 152)
    - Agreements, 1851-1864; holograph, 6pp. (Box 152)
    - Bills and receipts, 1851-1869; undated; holograph; 2 folders (Box 152)
    - Bills and receipts, 1870-1879; holograph (Box 153)
    - Enrollment and tuition, 1864-1878; undated; holograph (Box 153)
    - Correspondence, 1851-1892; undated; holograph (Box 153)
    - Incorporation, 1851-1858; holograph (Box 153)
    - Printed material, 1858-1889; broadsides, catalogues and clippings (Box 153)
    - Reports, 1861-1863; holograph, 4 leaves (Box 153)
    - Stock Assignments, undated; holograph (Box 153)